# Inkyu Shin | Curriculum Vitae

☑ dlsrbgg33@kaist.ac.kr

I am a third-year Ph.D. student at Korea Advanced Institute of Science and Technology (KAIST) under the co-supervision of Prof. Kuk-Jin Yoon and Prof. In So Kweon. I earned my B.S and M.S degrees in automotive engineering from Hanyang University(HYU) and KAIST in 2019 and 2021. I interned at NEC Laboratories America, Inc, San Jose, CA (with Dr. Yi-Hsuan Tsai), and Google Research (with Dr. Liang-Chieh Chen and Dr. Jun Xie). I am currently engaged in a research internship at TikTok.

### **Research Interests**

My research interest lies in computer vision, with a focus on developing effective learning method for processing data and building strong recognition/generation models. Specifically, I am interested in the following research topics:

#### Learning for Data-efficiency

Learning from Simulation Domain Adaptation Unsupervised Learning Self-supervised Learning

# Learning for Visual Recognition

Image Segmentation Video Segmentation

#### Learning for Generative AI

Video Editing

but also open to other explorable/challenging domains.

The ultimate purpose of these researches is to apply to a variety of applications (e.g., Autonomous driving, Robot Navigation, AR/VR).

# Research Experience

ByteDance / TikTok San Jose, CA Student Researcher Intern, Mentors: Liang-Chieh Chen and Qihang Yu Sep 5 - Current Google Research LA, CA (virtual) Student Researcher Intern, Mentors: Liang-Chieh Chen and Jun Xie May 2022 - April 2023 **NEC Laboratories America, Inc** San Jose, CA (virtual) Research Intern, Mentor: Yi-Hsuan Tsai May 2021 - Aug 2021 Korea University Seoul, Korea Research Intern, Supervisor: Jaegul Choo Sep 2018 - Dec 2018 **Hanyang University** Seoul, Korea Research Assistant, Supervisor: Myuong-Ho Sunwoo Jul 2018 - Aug 2018

#### **Education**

Korea Advanced Institute of Science and Technology (KAIST)

Puture Vehicle Ph.D. degree, Co-Advisors: Kuk-Jin Yoon and In So Kweon

2021–

Korea Advanced Institute of Science and Technology (KAIST)

Daejeon, Korea

Future Vehicle M.S degree, Advisor: In So Kweon
Master's Thesis: Learning to Scale the Labels for Self-training based Domain Adaptation

2019–2021

Hanyang University (HYU)

Seoul, Korea 2013–2019

AUTOMOTIVE ENGINEERING B.S degree

# **Publications**

(C: conference / J: journal / P: preprint / \* :equal contributions)

International Conference.....

o [C13] Video-kMaX: A Simple Unified Approach for Online and Near-Online Video Panoptic Segmentation

**Inkyu Shin**, Dahun Kim, Qihang Yu, Jun Xie, Hong-Seok Kim, Bradley Green, In So Kweon, Kuk-Jin Yoon, Liang-Chieh Chen

Winter Conference on Applications of Computer Vision (WACV) 2024

- Also presented at "Transformer For Vision" Workshops in conjuction with "CVPR, 2023
- [C12] MATE: Masked Autoencoders are Online 3D Test-Time Learners
   Muhammad Jehanzeb Mirza\*, Inkyu Shin\*, Wei Lin\*, Andreas Schriebl, Kunyang Sun, Jaesung Choe,
   Horst Possegger, Mateusz Kozinski, In So Kweon, Kuk-Jin Yoon, Horst Bischof
   ICCV, 2023
- [C11] TTA-COPE: Test-Time Adaptation for Category-Level Object Pose Estimation
   Taeyeop Lee, Jonathan Tremblay, Valts Blukis, Bowen Wen, Byeong-Uk Lee, Inkyu Shin, Stan Birchfield,
   In So Kweon, Kuk-Jin Yoon
   Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR), 2023
- [C10] Bidirectional Domain Mixup for Domain Adaptive Semantic Segmentation
  Daehan Kim\*, Minseok Seo\*, Kwanyong Park, Inkyu Shin, Sanghyun Woo
  Association for the Advancement of Artificial Intelligence (AAAI), 2023
- [C9] Learning Classifiers of Prototypes and Reciprocal Points for Universal Domain Adaptation Sungsu Hur, Inkyu Shin, Kwanyong Park, Sanghyun Woo, In So Kweon Winter Conference on Computer Vision (WACV), 2023
- [C8] Moving from 2D to 3D: volumetric medical image classification for rectal cancer staging
  Joohyung Lee\*, Jieun Oh\*, Inkyu Shin, You-sung Kim, Dae Kyung Sohn, Tae-sung Kim, In So Kweon
  Medical Image Computing and Computer Assisted Intervention (MICCAI), 2023
- [C7] MM-TTA: Multi-Modal Test-Time Adaptation for 3D Semantic Segmentation Inkyu Shin, Yi-Hsuan Tsai, Bingbing Zhuang, Samuel Schulter, Buyu Liu, Sparsh Garg, In So Kweon, Kuk-Jin Yoon

Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR), 2022

- Received Qualcomm Innovation Award 2022.
- o [C6] UDA-COPE: Unsupervised Domain Adaptation for Category-level Object Pose Estimation Taeyeop Lee, Byeong-Uk Lee, Inkyu Shin, Jaesung Choe, Ukcheol Shin, In So Kweon, Kuk-Jin Yoon Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR), 2022
- o [P2] Unsupervised Domain Adaptation for Video Semantic Segmentation Kwanyong Park\*, Inkyu Shin\*, Sanghyun Woo, In So Kweon

arXiv, 2021

- [C5] LabOR: Labeling Only if Required for Domain Adaptive Semantic Segmentation Inkyu Shin, Dong-Jin Kim, Jae Won Cho, Sanghyun Woo, Kwanyong Park, In So Kweon International Conference on Computer Vision (ICCV), 2021 (Oral)
  - Received Qualcomm Innovation Award 2021.
- [P1] Learning Representations by Contrasting Clusters While Bootstrapping Instances
  Junsoo Lee, Hojoon Lee, Inkyu Shin, Jaekyoung Bae, In So Kweon, Jaegul Choo
  arXiv, 2020
- [C4] Discover, Hallucinate, and Adapt:
   Open Compound Domain Adaptation for Semantic Segmentation
   Kwanyong Park, Sanghyun Woo, Inkyu Shin, In So Kweon
   Conference on Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS), 2020

   Received Qualcomm Innovation Award 2021.

Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR), 2019 (Oral)

- [C3] Two-phase Pseudo Label Densification for Self-training based Domain Adaptation Inkyu Shin, Sanghyun Woo, Fei pan, In So Kweon European Conference on Computer Vision (ECCV), 2020
  - Also presented at "Visual Learning with Limited Labels" Workshops in conjunction with (CVPR), 2020
- [C2] Unsupervised Intra-domain Adaptation for Semantic Segmentation through Self-Supervision
  Fei pan, Inkyu Shin, Francois Rameau, Seokju Lee, In So Kweon
  Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR), 2020 (Oral)
   Received Qualcomm Innovation Award 2020.
- o [C1] Image-to-Image Translation via Group-wise Deep Whitening-and-Coloring Transformation Wonwoong Cho, Sungha Choi, David Keetae Park, Inkyu Shin, Jaegul Choo

#### Awards

2022: Qualcomm Innovation Award2021: Qualcomm Innovation Award2020: Qualcomm Innovation Award

#### IT skills

- Languages: Python, MATLAB, C, LATEX
- o Libraries: PyTorch, TensorFlow

#### References

Prof. In So Kweon

Relationship: M.S & Ph.D Advisor Professor, Electrical Engineering, KAIST

Email: iskweon77@kaist.ac.kr

Prof. Kuk-Jin Yoon
 Relationship: Ph.D Advisor

 ${\sf Professor},\ {\sf Mechanical}\ {\sf Engineering},\ {\sf KAIST}$ 

Email: kjyoon@kaist.ac.kr

# o Dr. Yi-Hsuan Tsai

Relationship: Internship mentor at NEC Lab. (Previous) Research scientist, NEC Lab. (Current) AI/ML Tech Lead Manager, Google

Email: wasidennis@gmail.com

# o Dr. Liang-Chieh Chen

Relationship: Internship mentor at Google Research (Previous) Research scientist, Google Research (Current) Research scientist, ByteDance

Email: lcchen@cs.ucla.edu